mitpressjournals.org 2019-05-30

# Privacy Statement | MIT Press Journals

### Introduction

Your privacy is important to The MIT Press, and we are committed to respecting that privacy. This Privacy Statement explains how we handle and use the personal information we collect from The MIT Press website.

### What personal information we collect

While specific information may vary for particular individuals, we may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal information about you, which we have grouped together as follows:

  * Basic biographic/contact information – home and business addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, and social media contact information
  * Demographic information – names, gender, birth and death dates, photograph
  * Analytical information – aggregated information related to web visitor activity and email marketing actions

### How we collect personal information about you

In general, you can use The MIT Press website in all ways without using the technology known as "cookies." A cookie is a short identifier, stored on your computer, which a site may use to identify you when you make return visits to it. The features of The MIT Press site were designed to work without cookies, so if you turn them off, you may still browse, search, and shop at our site. Performance may be slower, however, and the "Remember Me" feature (for registered site users) will not function.

### How we use your personal information

We use your personal information for a number of legitimate purposes all in support of the MIT Press and its mission. Specifically, we use your personal information to:

  * We may collect anonymous information from visits to The MIT Press website to help us provide better customer service and a better customer experience. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit, and we measure aggregate user activity on The MIT Press website, but we do so in ways that keep user's personal identity and information anonymous. The MIT Press or the analytic vendors it selects may use this data to analyze site usage trends and statistics, to help us improve our website.
  * When we collect personal data from you in connection with a transaction (an order, e-mail request, etc.) we may extract some information about that transaction in an anonymous format and combine it with other anonymous information such as clickstream data. This anonymous information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patterns in our site's usage.

If you have concerns about any of these purposes, or how we communicate with you, please contact us at the MIT Press. We will always respect a request by you to stop processing your personal information (subject to our legal obligations).

### When we share your personal information

To perform the functions listed above, it may be necessary to share your personal information with 3rd party websites. The MIT Press is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these Web sites.

### How your information is stored and secured

The MIT Press uses risk-assessed administrative, technical and physical security measures to protect your personal information.

### How long we keep your personal information

The MIT Press retains information in accordance with applicable law, MIT Policy, or until you have been asked to delete.

### Rights for Individuals in the European Economic Area

You have the right in certain circumstances to (1) access your personal information; (2) to correct or erase information; (3) restrict processing; and (4) object to communications, direct marketing, or profiling. To the extent applicable, the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation provides further information about your rights. You also have the right to lodge complaints with your national or regional data protection authority.

If you are inclined to exercise these rights, we request an opportunity to discuss with you any concerns you may have. To protect the personal information we hold, we may also request further information to verify your identify when exercising these rights. Upon a request to erase information, we will maintain a core set of personal data to ensure we do not contact you inadvertently in the future, as well as any information necessary for the MIT Press archival purposes. We may also need to retain some financial information for legal purposes, including US IRS compliance. In the event of an actual or threatened legal claim, we may retain your information for purposes of establishing, defending against or exercising our rights with respect to such claim.

By providing information directly to the MIT Press, you consent to the transfer of your personal information outside of the European Economic Area to the United States. You understand that the current laws and regulations of the United States may not provide the same level of protection as the data and privacy laws and regulations of the EEA.

You are under no statutory or contractual obligation to provide any personal data to us.

### Additional Information

We may change this Privacy Statement from time to time. If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on the MIT Press website or by contacting you directly.

The controller for your personal information is the MIT Press. If you are in the EU and wish to assert any of your applicable GDPR rights, please contact: mitp-dpo@mit.edu

This policy was last updated June 2018.
